Guide to the Kerrigan Black Papers, 1963-1993
Department of Special Collections
Black, Kerrigan. Papers.,
1963-1993
M0752
Black, Kerrigan
7.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
A musician and composer whose one-man shows delighted and edified thousands of school children in the Bay Area. In the mid-1980s he developed an original one-man show called "Tryin' to get home" which was based on African American songs. Mr. Black was born in Chicago, received a BA from Stanford in 1975 and an MA in folklore from U.C. Berkeley. Includes compositions, files, photographs, sound recordings including an interview with Studs Terkel, video recordings, newsclippings, and biographical information including material from Black Gay Men United. Also included is a video, "To Marlon with love," 1992, a tribute to Marlon Riggs which includes some clips of Black talking and singing one of his songs.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1995.
Biography
A musician and composer whose one-man shows delighted and edified thousands of school children in the Bay Area. In the mid-1980s he developed an original one-man show called "Tryin' to get home" which was based on African American songs. Mr. Black was born in Chicago, received a BA from Stanford in 1975 and an MA in folklore from U.C. Berkeley.
Scope and Content
Includes compositions, files, photographs, sound recordings including an interview with Studs Terkel, video recordings, newsclippings, and biographical information including material from Black Gay Men United. Also included is a video, "To Marlon with love," 1992, a tribute to Marlon Riggs which includes some clips of Black talking and singing one of his songs.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Riggs, Marlon.; Black Gay Men United.; African Americans--Music.; Gay musicians.; Afro-American musicians.; Terkel, Studs.; The Kerrigan Black Show.; Tryin' to get home.
Collection Contents
- Biographical information: resumes and promotion biographies, diplomas, genealogy, TD Black (father), Black Gay Men United, obituaries. (Carton 1, Folder 1)
- Song compositions. Book 1 (A-N) (Carton 1, Folder 2)
- Song compositions. Book 2 (O-Z), unfinished songs, "For-A-Song" business. (Carton 1, Folder 3)
- Writings: published articles, newspaper writings, essays, "Impatient for Luck", interviews, letters. (Carton 2, Folder 1)
- Organizations worked with: Aerobics, Artworks, Jewish Home for the Aged, American Red Cross, Task Force AIDS Prevention, SF Symphony: Adventures in Music (AIM) Program, Arts for the Schools, Spectra, Young Audiences, and others. "The Kerrigan Black Show" cable television program. (Carton 2, Folder 2)
- Grants and Applications: Berkeley Civic Arts Fund, California Arts Council, National Black Programming Consortium, Clorox and Zellerbach Foundations. Business correspondence. Thank-you-notes to Kerrigan Black. (Carton 2, Folder 3)
- "Trying To Get Home": Performances, programs, newspaper notices, song lists, business correspondence, song lyrics, monologues, outline and production, contracts with Ralph Pavone. (Carton 3, Folder 1)
- "Trying To Get Home": Teachers Guide, letters of appreciation, canceled contracts due to death, contracts through young audiences. (Carton 3, Folder 2)
- "Trying To Get Home": Contracts 1990-92. Casuals and other gigs 1987-1991. (Carton 3, Folder 3)
- "Adventures in Music" (AIM) Program [1989-1990]. (Carton 4, Folder 1)
- "Music Talks!" [1991-1993]. (Carton 4, Folder 1)
- "Music Talks!" Songs. (Carton 4, Folder 1)
- Workshops with songs. "America Paints". Ross School Jazz Class. UC-extension, English language program. Hawthorne School, Black English program. (Carton 4, Folder 1)
- Publicity photos, club gigs, Song lists, set lists, Board and Care facilities. (Carton 4, Folder 2)
- Information material on: "Tryin' to get Home" (video), "The World that I see" (cassette tape), "Two Sides" (cassette tape), song writing classes, song plugging, Europe gigs - 1983, touring overseas, Ideas for songs and writings. (Carton 4, Folder 3)
- Video cassettes: Kerrigan Black television shows #s 1-4., (2 hours) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Video cassettes: Kerrigan Black television show #4 -, rough footage. (2 hours) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Video cassettes: Kerrigan Black television shows #s 5-8., (2 hours) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Video cassettes: Kerrigan Black television shows #s 9-12., (2 hours) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Video cassettes: Kerrigan Black: La Pena, [6/17/90 Father's Day]. "Trying to get Home", original footage. (2 hours) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Video cassettes: Kerrigan Black: "Trying to get Home" @ Hansberry, Edgewood Children's Center., (2 hours) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Black Renaissance (cable channel 44) interview [1990], "Sunday on 7" interview [1991], "Children of the Night" for the Gay Task Force on AIDS Prevention [1991], "America Paints" for Young Audiences [1991], Hawthorne Elementary School (SF) graduation graduates performing "Hold On To Your Dream" [1990], Aerobics tape made for friend's birthday [1991].1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- "Tryin' To Get Home: A History Of African American Song". Written and performed by Kerrigan Black. [1993] (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Kerrigan Black Memorial Service [March 27. 1993]., (2 hours) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Music cassettes: "When I Get To Have My Dream" (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Music cassettes: "Women in Distress" (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Music cassettes: "When I Finally Fall in Love" (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Music cassettes: "Someone is Watching Over Me", "He'll Never Let You Down", How Long has this Soul Been Traveling?", "I'm Goin' Home". (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Music cassettes: Interview re: Hawthorne Language Development. [1989] (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Music cassettes: Studs Terkel interviews Kerrigan Black. [1963/89] (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Music cassettes: Music for "Intro to Jazz" (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Music cassettes: Jazz Recordings for Lectures. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Music cassettes: Jazz Lecture Music. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Music cassettes: "Tryin' to get home". (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Music cassettes: "Tryin' to get home". SF Museum of Modern Art. [[1992] (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Music cassettes: "Children of the Night" in association with the National Task Force on AIDS Prevention. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Music cassettes: Kerrigan Black: "Two Sides". [1984] (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Music cassettes: Kerrigan Black: "Ya Gotta Know Somethin' 'Bout History" and Hold on to Your Dream". [1991] (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Music cassettes: Kerrigan Black: "The World that I See" [1993] (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Kerrigan Black T-Shirt: "Ya Gotta Know Somethin' 'Bout History So The World Isn't Just A Mystery!" (Box 7, Folder 1)
- "The San Francisco Bay Guardian". [May 1-8, 1980] (Box 7, Folder 2)
- "Express. The East Bay's Free Weekly". [December 14, 1990] (Box 7, Folder 3)